<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
   "http://www.docbook.org/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [

<!ELEMENT xi:include (xi:fallback?) >
<!ATTLIST xi:include
    xmlns:xi   CDATA      #FIXED     "http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    href       CDATA      #REQUIRED
    parse      (xml|text) "xml"
    encoding   CDATA      #IMPLIED >
<!ELEMENT xi:fallback ANY>
<!ATTLIST xi:fallback
    xmlsn:xi   CDATA      #FIXED     "http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" >
<!ENTITY % local.chapter.class "| xi:include">
<!ENTITY % local.section.class "| xi:include">
]>

<!-- FILE        : Scalytic.xml
     SUBJECT     : Master document for the Scalytic documentation set.
     AUTHOR      : (C) Copyright 2014 by Peter C. Chapin <PChapin@vtc.vsc.edu>

This is the documentation for the Scalytic compiler plugin. -->

<book status="draft">
  <bookinfo>
    <title>Augusta</title>
    <author>
      <firstname>Peter</firstname>
      <surname>Chapin</surname>
      <othername role="mi">C.</othername>
      <affiliation>
        <orgname>Vermont Technical College</orgname>
        <orgdiv>Computer Information Systems Department</orgdiv>
      </affiliation>
    </author>
    <authorinitials>pcc</authorinitials>
    <copyright>
      <year>2014</year>
      <holder>Peter C. Chapin</holder>
    </copyright>
    <legalnotice>
      <para> Permission is granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the
        terms of the GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.1 or any later version published
        by the Free Software Foundation; with the Invariant Sections being LIST THEIR TITLES,
        with the Front-Cover Texts being LIST, and with the Back-Cover Texts being LIST. A copy
        of the license is included in the section entitled "GNU Free Documentation License".
      </para>
    </legalnotice>
    <!-- Do we really want to include this revision history now? -->
    <revhistory>
      <revision>
        <revnumber>1.0</revnumber>
        <date>2020-12-31</date>
        <authorinitials>pcc</authorinitials>
        <revremark>This is a work in progress with no definitive release schedule.</revremark>
      </revision>
    </revhistory>
  </bookinfo>
  <preface id="Introduction">
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>Scalytic is an analysis tool for Scala programs implemented as a Scala compiler
      plugin. The precise goals and features of the tool are under development and thus this
      document is continuously evolving. Scalytic is a research project with the long term goal
      of providing formal verification for Scala programs in a way that extends the current
      state of the art for formal verification in a Scala context.</para>

    <para>This document primarily targets users and developers of Scalytic. The technical
      details of Scalytic's design and theoretical underpinnings are documented by the academic
      papers and related documents also stored in this repository.</para>

    <para>Conceptually Scalytic project provides four components.</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>The definition of a Scala subset, called <emphasis>Sca</emphasis>, representing
          the part of Scala over which Scalytic can perform its analysis. Scalytic only
          processes constructs that are in the Sca subset as defined by this document.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>The specification of annotations that can be used by the programmer to enrich
          interface information with various kinds of contracts. Some of these annotations are
          executable and can thus play a role in the dynamic testing of Scalytic
          programs.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>A plugin for the Scala compiler that generates verification conditions (or "proof
          obligations," we use the terms interchangeably) in a suitable intermediate
          verification language such as <ulink url="http://why3.lri.fr/">why3</ulink>.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para>Tool support for processing the generated verification conditions using standard
          theorem provers such as <ulink url="http://alt-ergo.lri.fr/">alt-ergo</ulink> and/or
            <ulink url="http://coq.inria.fr/what-is-coq">Coq</ulink>.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <!-- Include disclaimer. -->

  </preface>

  <xi:include href="Build.xml"/>
  <xi:include href="User.xml"/>
  <xi:include href="Design.xml"/>

  <!-- <bibliography> ... </bibliography> -->

</book>
